# Marie Koesnodihardjo

mkoesnod@gmail.com | (650) 421-5043 | San Francisco, CA

## Summary

Energetic leader with strong communication and organizational skills. Passionate about developing strategic web solutions for socially responsible companies that increase social presence and drive global impact. When faced with challenges, I craft solutions using research, smart goals, and visual mapping. I am a team player with the mindset that no task is off-limits, and there is nothing I can't learn to do.

# **Education**

#### Job Train - Web Development

June 2016 - Present

16-week course focused on HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Git, WordPress, and Agile Software Development

### University of California, Berkeley, College of Natural Resources

August 2010 - May 2014

B.S. Conservation of Natural Resources Focus: Sustainable Business Development

## **Experience**

#### Earl's Organic Produce

December 2014 - June 2016

Marketing & Sustainability Assistant

- Created first Marketing & Sustainability Assistant position to drive Earl's vision for organic, sustainable living
- Developed customer affinity campaign across 4 platforms resulting in over 4,000 new followers of eco-friendly living
- Spearheaded website re-design and executed digital marketing strategies and tactics to increase SEO and SEM traffic
- Analyzed latest environmental metrics for storylines and contributed content for Annual Sustainability Report
- Resident expert on delivering in-store product demos to drive sales
- Designed customer on-boarding process to attract and retain high profile customers

Accounting & Administrative Assistant

- Streamlined all reconciled accounts by training co-workers on using Microsoft Access to analyze customer data in lieu of a CRM system
- Decreased the rate of lost and misplaced items by restructuring AR & AP paperwork flow and storage process

## One World Play Project

September 2014 - December 2014

Giving Team Intern

- Created dashboards to monitor customer data distribution of over 1 million international soccer ball donations
- Conducted evaluation surveys to gather stories highlighting impact of donations on non-profit programs
- Presented Benefit Corporation's (B-Corp) renewal strategic plan to upper management

#### Cal Alumni Association - Lair of the Golden Bear

Summer 2011 - 2014

Head of Maintenance

- Received consistent and outstanding team reviews for maintaining safe and sanitary camp facilities
- Served as a role model for youth while providing excellent customer service to 350 camper families

### Leadership

# Campowerment - Women's Empowerment Camp

March 2013 - Present

West Coast Operations

- Lead staff meetings and ensure timely execution of activities in a highly emotional environment
- Empower +100 women to create actionable plans to reach their personal and professional goals

#### **Student Organic Gardening Association**

2012 - 2014

President & Student Teacher

- Led community of 220 students in organic gardening and project management courses
- Increased campus presence by allocating \$3,000 budget to campus-wide workshops and student projects

Professional Athlete 2008 – 2010

Artistic Roller Skater for Puerto Rican Olympic Federation

- 15 year career culminating in international competition at the 2011 Pan-Am & 2010 Central American Games

# **Skills & Interests**

**Technical:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Command Line, Hootsuite, Microsoft Excel & Access, Google Spreadsheets, Virtual Accountmate, Basecamp

Language: Conversational Spanish

Interests: Roller Skating, Organic Farming, Women's Empowerment, Cooking, Yoga